AIMAN SIDDIQUI

9288 W Atlantic Blvd Apt# 1122, Coral Springs, FL 33071 | (321) 270-7536 | aimansiddiqui90@gmail.com

Website, Portfolio, Profiles

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/aimansiddiqui/
- https://github.com/Aiman-Siddiqui

Professional Summary

Versatile IT professional with 6+ years of work experience in Database management, Project management, Web development, and Content management roles. Background in taking extensive and complex projects to completion through constant communication and Give-and-Take negotiations with team and business. Ability to find and improve system drawbacks. I have developed a three-tier web-based application that made use of servlets and JSP to get and meet requests from the server; MySQL and JDBC were used to access and manipulate database. Apart from work projects, I have also worked on some projects in my personal time making use of MongoDB, MailChimp, and PyCharm. Frequently praised as proactive by peers, I can be relied upon to help the company achieve its goals.

Skills

•Programming Skills:

Java, JavaScript, Python

•Front End Development:

HTML, CSS, Angular, JSP

•Back End Development:

MS Database, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, REST APIs, Node.js, Express

Project Management:

Agile, Jira, Confluence, TeamSite, GitHub, WebEx, Skype

•Tools and Software:

Visual Studio Code, Brackets, PyCharm, Mongo Shell, CMD, Eclipse, MailChimp, Postman, MS Office, Adobe Suite

•Soft Skills:

Communication, Problem solving, User training, Workflow planning, Strategic content planning, Content editing, Time management, Teamwork

Work History

UI Developer/Digital Content Manager

10/2020 to Current

Citibank - CORAL SPRINGS, FL

- Managed Websites and UI with Javascript and Angular codebase.
- Determine project objectives by deeply understanding business and requestors requirements.
- Improved business function by evaluating existing practice and suggesting and implementing a modification.
- Performed content changes for live web applications.
- Directed content of website by gathering information and integrating data from other departments.
- Used Content Management System to manage content distribution.
- Maintained content marketing calendar to schedule creation and delivery deadlines.
- Collaborated with marketing and business to develop and plan site content, layout, and style.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

08/2020 to Current

TATA Consultancy Service – NJ

- Created a web application which using JSP allowed users to send requests to the server where servlet handled the request and performed business logic to send back the results to client
- JDBC and MySQL performed database manipulation
- Created a single page web application using MEAN stack
- The website allowed users to fetch current weather and weather forecasts, get sports news and live chat with other users
- The website achieved appealing user interface using CSS and bootstrap and authentication for admin or user was achieved using JWT tokens
- Developed a real-time chat app that made use of the Socket.io framework of Node.js
- The app had the functionality to provide options to join different rooms for specific interests
- Develop, test, implement, and maintain web applications
- Manage to meet required deadlines in accordance with sprints
- Attend daily stand-ups with team to keep project on track
- Maintain effective communication with the team to meet the deliverables.
- Installed and configured software applications and tested solutions for functionality.
- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code for software system, forming core framework.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.

DATABASE MANAGER

06/2015 to 07/2020

SourceOne Products – Orlando, FL

• Using Microsoft Excel, creates and maintains database to organize the company's valuable data in an easy to

work with manner.

- Performs troubleshooting, backup, recovery, and migration of databases to keep the operation moving without delays.
- Migrates data to other user's devices on the company network to ease the process of collaboration.
- Performs a daily backup of databases to deal with technological accidents.
- Use macros and formulas to automate the process of extracting and loading data from and into the databases for timely completion of the projects.
- Occasionally use Microsoft Access and SQL statements to make better sense of the data using the relational database structure.
- Records sales and purchases.
- Have worked in teams of 3 or 4 people to meet deadlines and exceed the production goals.
- Using Adobe suite, creates databases of images of current inventory in hand.
- Generate and keep daily technical reports by collecting and analyzing online traffic trends
- Develop, implement, and manage all online content for the various e-commerce website storefronts (description, images, keywords).
- Read and analyze web traffic and customer behavior to improve our content strategies.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S: Computer Information Technology

UNIVERSITY oF CENTRAL - Orlando, FL

- Dean's List [2015]
- President's List [2016]
- International Dean's List Society,
- GPA: 3.6

Certifications

- Computer Programming Specialist (Valencia College)
- Computer Information Data Specialist (Valencia College)
- Computer Information Technology Specialist (Valencia College)
- Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python by IBM
- Python for Data Science, AI & Development by IBM

Languages

English	Urdu
Full Professional	Native or Bilingual
	Native of Brinigual
Hindi	
Native or Bilingual	